# **ANIL KUL**

I am a computer engineer that focus on deep learning and computer vision in my career. I have proven records of work discipline with my work experiences, researches in reputable laboratories, startup, internship and working experiences. I want to expand my domain knowledge with new deep learning projects.



## **CONTACT**

akul16@ku.edu.tr

**+90 554 5019785** 

Istanbul Turkey

@anilkul98

in Anıl Kul

## **SKILLS**

Scrum

#### Software Engineering

**Full Stack Development MERN Stack** Java **Javascript** 

**Machine Learning** Python **Pytorch** Tensorflow/Keras Scikit-learn Data Preprocessing/analysis

(numpy, scipy, pandas)

Visualisation

## Computer Vision Domain Knowledge

**Medical Applications Semantic Segmentation Image Classification Object Detection Satellite Image Segmentation** Offline Handwriting Recognition 

Output 

#### Soft Skills

I have presentation, team management, strategic planning and business development experiences due to my startup and university club membership.

#### Languages

**English** German



## ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

- ▼ Vehbi Koc Scholar (Given for 3.5+ SPA)
- Dean's High Honor Roll (Given for 3.0+ SPA)
- Merit-based full scholarship
- Vice President of IEEE student branch
- Duke of Edinburgh's Award

## **EDUCATION**

**10/2021 - 08/2023** 

Technical University of Munich, Munich Master of Computer Science

**1** 09/2016 - 06/2021

**Bachelor of Computer Engineering ♥** Koc University, Istanbul

GPA: 3.31 / 4.0

**1** 09/2017 - 06/2021

**Bachelor of Business Administration ♥** Koc University, Istanbul

GPA: 3.31 / 4.0

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## 03/2022 - Present

SAP, Munich

**Working Student** 

Job Description:

I am working in a smart SAP service project as a data scientist. I am working with next action prediction, NLP techniques and image vectorization.

**11/2021 - 03/2022** 

**Q** Avantgarde, Munich

Machine Learning Engineer

Job Definition:

Worked on facial expression, age, gender and attention extraction from videos.

**1** 03/2021 - 11/2021

**Ocipher Analytics**, İstanbul

Machine Learning Engineer

**Projects:** 

- Biodiversity Detection From Satellite Images: The aim of the project is detecting the areas with high biodiversity from satellite images that are taken from Sentinel2 API
- Acute Otitis Media Diagnose: The otoscope videos are used for training and product level. Worked with Autoencoders and clustering for frame selection from videos.
- Tooth Decay Diagnose: The bitewing Xrays has used for training and product level. Decayed tooth and the the areas are determined with the help of DL classifiers and class activation maps.

**6** 06/2020 - 03/2021

**♥** Koc University IUI Lab

**Undergraduate Research Assistant** 

Project:

The aim of the project is extraction of Stylized Powerpoint slides from offline and online handwritten documents. or this project, I am working with tensorflow and OpenCv. We are using the YOLO, CNN and EAST models in our pipeline.

**1** 04/2019 - 06/2020

**♀** Triprouter

Co-Founder

Description:

TripRouter is a mobile platform that make best trip plan according to users' personal preferences by an artificial intelligence algorithm.

## **PROJECTS**

**1** 09/2020 - 01/2021

**Senior Design Project Project Description:** 

**Smart Cook Assistant** 

A mobile application that can identify food type from Image, give nutrition and recipe information. Also it is integrated with virtual market applications for easier grocery ordering. We create a Turkish Food dataset. We use Inception-v3 model for food classification

**1** 09/2020 - 01/2021

**♀** Intro. to Deep Learning Project

Food Detection for Pos Machines

**Project Description:** 

We are designing an android application that can detect all foods in a tray and automatically gives the total check to the cashier. We use YOLO-v4.x